<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.championpeak87.cosmic-ext-classic-menu</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-only</project_license>
  <project_group>COSMIC</project_group>
  <developer_name>Kamil Lihan</developer_name>
  <update_contact>k.lihan@outlook.com</update_contact>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/championpeak87/cosmic-ext-classic-menu</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/championpeak87/cosmic-ext-classic-menu/issues</url>
  <url type="help">https://github.com/championpeak87/cosmic-ext-classic-menu#readme</url>
  <url type="contact">mailto:k.lihan@outlook.com</url>
  <name>COSMIC Classic Menu</name>
  <summary>A launcher applet for COSMIC Desktop</summary>
  <description xml:lang="en">
    <p>
      COSMIC Classic Menu is a launcher applet for the COSMIC Desktop environment, providing quick access to applications, system functions, and settings. Features include:
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Browse and launch installed applications via a clear menu</li>
      <li>Search for apps by name or category</li>
      <li>Customize button appearance (icon, label, combination, auto style)</li>
      <li>Quick access to recently used applications</li>
      <li>Change menu and search field position</li>
      <li>Multi-language support (localization)</li>
      <li>Modern design and theme compatibility</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Ideal for users who want fast app launching, menu customization, or an overview of frequently used programs. Perfect for COSMIC Desktop, but usable as a standalone launcher.
    </p>
  </description>
  <description xml:lang="cs">
    <p>
      COSMIC Classic Menu je spouštěcí applet pro prostředí COSMIC Desktop, který nabízí rychlý přístup k aplikacím, systémovým funkcím a nastavením. Umožňuje:
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Procházet a spouštět nainstalované aplikace pomocí přehledného menu</li>
      <li>Vyhledávat aplikace podle názvu nebo kategorie</li>
      <li>Přizpůsobit vzhled tlačítka (ikona, popisek, kombinace, automatický styl)</li>
      <li>Rychlý přístup k naposledy použitým aplikacím</li>
      <li>Možnost změny pozice menu a vyhledávacího pole</li>
      <li>Podpora více jazyků (lokalizace)</li>
      <li>Moderní design a kompatibilita s různými motivy</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Applet je vhodný pro uživatele, kteří chtějí rychle spouštět aplikace, upravovat vzhled menu, nebo mít přehled o svých nejčastěji používaných programech. Je ideální pro desktopové prostředí COSMIC, ale lze jej použít i jako samostatný launcher.
    </p>
  </description>
  <description xml:lang="de">
    <p>
      COSMIC Classic Menu ist ein Starter-Applet für die COSMIC Desktop-Umgebung und bietet schnellen Zugriff auf Anwendungen, Systemfunktionen und Einstellungen. Funktionen:
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Installierte Anwendungen über ein übersichtliches Menü durchsuchen und starten</li>
      <li>Apps nach Name oder Kategorie suchen</li>
      <li>Button-Design anpassen (Icon, Text, Kombination, automatisch)</li>
      <li>Schneller Zugriff auf zuletzt verwendete Anwendungen</li>
      <li>Position des Menüs und Suchfelds ändern</li>
      <li>Mehrsprachige Unterstützung (Lokalisierung)</li>
      <li>Modernes Design und Theme-Kompatibilität</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Ideal für Nutzer, die Anwendungen schnell starten, das Menü anpassen oder einen Überblick über häufig genutzte Programme haben möchten. Perfekt für COSMIC Desktop, aber auch als eigenständiger Launcher nutzbar.
    </p>
  </description>
  <description xml:lang="fr">
    <p>
      COSMIC Classic Menu est un applet de lancement pour l'environnement COSMIC Desktop, offrant un accès rapide aux applications, fonctions système et paramètres. Fonctionnalités :
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Parcourir et lancer les applications installées via un menu clair</li>
      <li>Rechercher des applications par nom ou catégorie</li>
      <li>Personnaliser l'apparence du bouton (icône, texte, combinaison, style automatique)</li>
      <li>Accès rapide aux applications récemment utilisées</li>
      <li>Changer la position du menu et du champ de recherche</li>
      <li>Support multilingue (localisation)</li>
      <li>Design moderne et compatibilité avec les thèmes</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Idéal pour les utilisateurs souhaitant lancer rapidement des applications, personnaliser le menu ou avoir un aperçu des programmes fréquemment utilisés. Parfait pour COSMIC Desktop, mais utilisable comme lanceur autonome.
    </p>
  </description>
  <description xml:lang="es">
    <p>
      COSMIC Classic Menu es un applet lanzador para el entorno COSMIC Desktop, que proporciona acceso rápido a aplicaciones, funciones del sistema y configuraciones. Características:
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Explora y lanza aplicaciones instaladas mediante un menú claro</li>
      <li>Busca aplicaciones por nombre o categoría</li>
      <li>Personaliza la apariencia del botón (icono, etiqueta, combinación, estilo automático)</li>
      <li>Acceso rápido a aplicaciones usadas recientemente</li>
      <li>Cambia la posición del menú y del campo de búsqueda</li>
      <li>Soporte multilingüe (localización)</li>
      <li>Diseño moderno y compatibilidad con temas</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Ideal para usuarios que desean lanzar aplicaciones rápidamente, personalizar el menú o tener una visión general de los programas más utilizados. Perfecto para COSMIC Desktop, pero también utilizable como lanzador independiente.
    </p>
  </description>
  <description xml:lang="ru">
    <p>
      COSMIC Classic Menu — это апплет-лаунчер для среды COSMIC Desktop, обеспечивающий быстрый доступ к приложениям, системным функциям и настройкам. Возможности:
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Просмотр и запуск установленных приложений через удобное меню</li>
      <li>Поиск приложений по названию или категории</li>
      <li>Настройка внешнего вида кнопки (иконка, подпись, комбинация, авто)</li>
      <li>Быстрый доступ к недавно использованным приложениям</li>
      <li>Изменение положения меню и поля поиска</li>
      <li>Многоязычная поддержка (локализация)</li>
      <li>Современный дизайн и совместимость с темами</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Идеально подходит для пользователей, которым нужен быстрый запуск приложений, настройка меню или обзор часто используемых программ. Отлично подходит для COSMIC Desktop, но может использоваться как отдельный лаунчер.
    </p>
  </description>
  <description xml:lang="ja">
    <p>
      COSMIC Classic MenuはCOSMIC Desktop環境向けのランチャーアプレットで、アプリケーション、システム機能、設定への迅速なアクセスを提供します。主な機能：
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>分かりやすいメニューでインストール済みアプリを閲覧・起動</li>
      <li>名前やカテゴリでアプリを検索</li>
      <li>ボタンの外観をカスタマイズ（アイコン、ラベル、組み合わせ、自動スタイル）</li>
      <li>最近使用したアプリへの素早いアクセス</li>
      <li>メニューや検索フィールドの位置を変更</li>
      <li>多言語対応（ローカライズ）</li>
      <li>モダンなデザインとテーマ互換性</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      アプリの素早い起動やメニューのカスタマイズ、よく使うプログラムの一覧が欲しいユーザーに最適です。COSMIC Desktopに最適ですが、単体ランチャーとしても利用可能です。
    </p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.championpeak87.cosmic-ext-classic-menu.desktop</launchable>
  <icon type="remote">https://github.com/championpeak87/cosmic-ext-classic-menu/raw/main/res/icons/hicolor/scalable/apps/com.championpeak87.cosmic-ext-classic-menu.svg</icon>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://github.com/championpeak87/cosmic-ext-classic-menu/raw/main/screenshots/main.png</image>
      <caption>Main menu screenshot</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <categories>
    <category>Utility</category>
    <category>System</category>
    <category>Launcher</category>
    <category>Desktop</category>
  </categories>
  <provides>
    <id>com.championpeak87.cosmic-ext-classic-menu</id>
    <mimetypes>
      <mimetype>text/plain</mimetype>
    </mimetypes>
    <binaries>
      <binary>cosmic-ext-classic-menu</binary>
    </binaries>
  </provides>
  <releases>
    <release version="0.0.9" date="2025-11-19">
      <description>
        <h1>What's changed</h1>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix flatpak issues</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.8" date="2025-10-25">
      <description>
        <h1>What's changed</h1>
        <ul>
          <li>Resolve performance issues</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.7" date="2025-10-17">
      <description>
        <h1>What's changed</h1>
        <ul>
          <li>Rename applet to cosmic-ext-classic-menu</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.6" date="2025-09-29">
      <description>
        <h1>What's changed</h1>
        <ul>
          <li>Resolve performance issues</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.5" date="2025-09-27">
      <description>
        <h1>What's changed</h1>
        <ul>
          <li>Patch popup positioning</li>
          <li>Ability to set custom icon</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.4" date="2025-09-24">
      <description>
        <h1>What's changed</h1>
        <ul>
          <li>Add configuration options</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.3" date="2025-09-11">
      <description>
        <h1>What's changed</h1>
        <ul>
          <li>Fix launching applications in flatpak version of the applet</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.2" date="2025-05-17">
      <description>
        <h1>What's changed</h1>
        <ul>
          <li>Layout updates</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="0.0.1-preview" date="2025-05-12">
      <description>
        <p>Initial test release</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
